Pease, Arthur Stanley, 1881-1964. Arthur Stanley Pease correspondence and compositions, 1870-1963 (MS Am 1804): Guide.
Arthur Stanley Pease correspondence and compositions,
- III. Other letters
  - O'Hara, Barratt. 1 letter to Sherwood Washburn; 1958. With a note from Henrietta (Pease) Washburn to Arthur Stanley Pease., (1130)
  - Oldfather, William Abbott, 1880-1945. 1 letter (copy) to Robert Daniel Carmichael; 1941., (1131)
  - Oldfather, William Abbott, 1880-1945. 1 letter (copy) to George Lincoln Hendrickson; 1936., (1132)
  - Oldfather, William Abbott, 1880-1945. 1 letter (copy) to K.H. Ishii; 1940., (1133)
  - Oldfather, William Abbott, 1880-1945. 2 letters (copies) to Lucius Rogers Shero; 1944., (1134)
  - Oldfather, William Abbott, 1880-1945. 1 letter (copy) to Stanley Barney Smith; 1944., (1135)
  - Otis, Brooks. 3 letters to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; 1951 and [n.d.], (1136)
  - Otis, Christine. 1 letter to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; 1951., (1137)
  - Park, John Edgar, 1879- 1 letter (copy) to Vaughan Dabney; 1932., (1138)
  - Pease, Abby Frances (Cutter) 1 letter to Isabel Chapin Barrows; 1893., (1139)
  - Pease, Abby Frances (Cutter) 1 letter to (Mrs.) Herbert E. Greene; 1906., (1140)
  - Pease, (Mrs.) C.B. 1 letter to Theodore Claudius Pease; 1881., (1141)
  - Pease, Henrietta (Faxon) 1 letter to Brooks, Otis; [1919], (1142)
  - Pease, Theodore Claudius, d.1893. 1 letter to [Samuel June] Barrows; 1870., (1143)
  - Pease, Theodore Claudius, d.1893. 1 letter to Isabel Chapin Barrows; 1882., (1144)
  - Perry, Ben Edwin, 1892- 1 letter (copy) to Edward Capps; 1945., (1145)
  - Perry, Bliss, 1860-1954. 1 letter to [Christine] Otis; 1951., (1146)
  - Pharr, Clyde, 1883. 2 letters to Edward Kennard Rand; 1942., (1147)
  - Place, Perley Oakland, 1872- 1 letter (copy) to [Florence K. Leetch];1937., (1148)
  - Plimpton, George Arthur, 1885-1936. 1 letter (copy) to Roy Caston Flickinger; 1932., (1149)
  - Plimpton, George Arthur, 1885-1936. 1 letter to Edward Kennard Rand; 1927., (1150)
  - Post, Levi Arnold, 1889- 1 letter to Austin M. Harmon; 1945., (1151)
  - Post, Levi Arnold, 1889- 2 letters (carbon copies) to William Abbott Oldfather; 1938., (1152)
  - Postgate, John Percival, 1853-1926. 2 letters to Harrison E. Cunningham; 1922., (1153)
  - Radford, Robert Somerville, 1869- 1 letter (mimeographed) to Roy Caston Flickinger; 1932., (1154)
  - Rand, Edward Kennard, 1871-1945. 1 letter (copy) to Mason Hammond; 1932., (1155)
  - Rand, Edward Kennard, 1871-1945. 1 letter (copy) to Harvard University Press; 1932., (1156)
  - Rand, Edward Kennard, 1871-1945. 1 letter (copy) Ernest Gottlieb Sihler; 1934., (1157)
  - Rhees, Rush, 1860-1939. 1 letter to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; 1931., (1158)
  - Robinson, Rodney Potter; 1890- 1 letter to Austin M. Harmon; 1945., (1159)
  - Ropes, James Hardy, 1866-1933. 2 letters (copies) to Frederick Harlan Page; 1932., (1160)
  - Sanders, Henry Arthur, 1868- 1 letter (copy) to George Lincoln Hendrickson;1942., (1161)
  - Sarton, George, 1884-1956. 1 letter (mimeographed to Vilhjálmur Stefánsson;) 1946., (1162)
  - Schultes, Richard Evans. 3 letters (copies) to Academic press; 1962., (1163)
  - Schultes, Richard Evans. 2 letters (copies) Harvard University Press; 1961., (1164)
  - Semple, William Tunstall. 1 letter to Austin M. Harmon; 1945., (1165)
  - Shero, Lucius Rogers. 2 letters (copies) to William Abbott Oldfather; 1944, (1166)
  - Sjogren, Hakan, 1870- 1 letter to Harrison E. Cunningham; 1922., (1167)
  - Souter, Alexander, 1873-1949. 1 letter (copy) to Lucius Rogers Shero; 1941., (1168)
  - Starck, Taylor, 1889- 1 letter (copy) to Paul Herman Buck; 1950., (1169)
  - Stearns, Edward R. 1 letter (copy) to [Oliver D.] Sewall; 1932., (1170)
  - [Stocker, Arthur Frederick] 1 letter (copy) to John Huston Finley; 1940., (1171)
  - [Stocker, Arthur Frederick] 1 letter (copy) to Florence K. Leetch; 1946., (1172)
  - [Stocker, Arthur Frederick] 2 letters (copies) to the Committee on the Sheldon Fund; 1941., (1173)
  - Tavenner, Eugene, 1878- 1 letter (copy) to Henry Rushton Fairclough; 1936., (1174)
  - Taylor, Lily Ross, 1886- 1 letter (copy) to William Abbott Oldfather; 1944., (1175)
  - Thornton, Harrison Robertson, 1858-1893. 1 letter to Theodore Claudius Pease; 1893., (1176)
  - Ullman, Berthold Louis, 1882- 1 letter (copy) to Roy Caston Flickinger; 1934., (1177)
  - Washburn, Henrietta (Pease) 1 letter to Abby Frances (Cutter) Pease; [1919] With a letter by Arthur Stanley Pease., (1178)
  - Washburn, Henrietta (Pease) 5 letters to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; 1921- [1960] and [n.d.], (1179)
  - Washburn, Stanley. 2 letters to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; [n.d.], (1180)
  - Webster, Hutton, 1875- 1 letter to George Foot Moore; 1924., (1181)
  - Weigle, Luther Allan, 1880- 1 letter (copy) to Vaughan Dabney; 1932., (1182)
  - West, Andrew Fleming, 1853-1943. 2 letters to George Foot Moore; 1923-1924., (1183)
  - Woods, Eleanor H. 1 letter to Abby Frances (Cutter) Pease; 1920., (1184)
  - Woodworth, Allegra. 1 letter to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; [n.d.], (1185)
  - Macmillan, firm, publishers, recipient. 2 letters (copies) from an unddentified correspondent; 1917. Concerning Arthur Stanley Pease's Greek Literature for English Readers., (1186)
  - Pease, Henrietta Faxon, recipient. 1 letter, from [ ]; [1931], (1187)
  - Schultes, Richard Evans, recipient. 1 letter (copy) from [ ]; 1956., (1188)
  - Washburn, Henrietta (Pease), recipient. 1 letter from [ ]; [n.d.], (1189)
  - Washburn, Sherwood Larned, 1911, recipient. 1 letter from [ ]; 1953., (1190)
- IV. Compositions
  - Allen, Bernard Meredith, 1864- A footnote to the history of academic freedom. TS.s. (mimeographed); [n.p., n.d.] 1 v., (1191)
  - American philological association. [Miscellaneous reports] TS. (unsigned); [n.p.] 1932-1938., (1192); 32s.(32p.)
  - Amherst college. [Statement on the resignation of Arthur Stanley Pease as President] MS.s. and TS.s.; [Amherst, 1932], (1193); 3s.(3p.)
    Signed by Arthur Rugg,; Calvin Coolidge, and George D. Pratt.
  - Bayley, Elise Hewitt. A word in memory. TS.s.; [n.p.] 8 Jan 1952., (1194); 2s.(2p.)
    In memory of Henrietta (Faxon) Pease.
  - Bolaffio, Robert. Last words of Gaetano Salvemini. TS. (photocopy); [n.p., ca.1957], (1195); 5s.(5p.)
  - Carmichael, Robert Daniel, 1879- [William Abbott Oldfather] TS. (unsigned); [n.p.] 29 Nov 1945., (1196); 9s.(9p.)
    Also by Ben Edwin Perry and Henry Baldwin Ward.
  - Chambers, Mortimer Hardin, 1927- A student looks at humane scholarship. TS.s. (mimeographed); [n.p., Jun 1954], (1197); 4s.(4p.)
    A press release.
  - Fernald, Merritt Lyndon, 1873- Newfoundland expedition, 1925. TS.s. (carbon copy); [n.p.] 16 May-9Jun 1925., (1198); 4s.(4p.)
  - [Finley, John Huston, 1904- ] [Carl Newell Jackson] TS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (1199); 4s.(4p.)
  - Hammond, Mason, 1903- [Edward Kennard Rand] TS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (1200); 5s.(5p.)
  - Otis, W. 200th anniversary of the speech of James Otis against the writs of assistance. TS.s. (carbon copy); [n.p.] 24 Feb 1961., (1201); 5s.(5p.)
  - Pease, Arthur Stanley, 1881-1964. The apple of the eye. TS. (unsigned); [n.p., Jan 1943], (1202); 1s.(1p.)
    A criticism of a paper by Marbury Bladen Ogle.
  - Pease, Arthur Stanley, 1881-1964. [Botanical notes on Essex County] A.MS.s., [n.p., n.d.] 1 v., (1203)
  - Pease, Arthur Stanley, 1881-1964. [Botanical notes on Essex County] TS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (1204); 38s.(38p.)
  - Pease, Arthur Stanley, 1881-1964. A.MS. diaries; [v.p.]; [1880]-11 Mar 1961. 41 v., (1205)
  - Pease, Arthur Stanley, 1881-1964. [Edward Kennard Rand] A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (1206); 7s.(8p.)
  - Pease, Arthur Stanley, 1881-1964. Notes on mountain-climbing in antiquity. A.MS.s.; [n.p., n.d.], (1207); 13s.(13p.)
  - Pease, Arthur Stanley, 1881-1964. [Randolph Mountain Club] A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., 1949], (1208); 2s.(3p.)
  - Pease, Arthur Stanley, 1881-1964. [Speeches at the laying of the cornerstone of the Folger Library] TS. (carbon copy, unsigned); [n.p.] Oct 1927., (1209); 6s.(6p.)
  - Pease, Arthur Stanley, 1881-1964. [Miscellaneous notes] A.MS.; [v.p., v.d.], (1210); 1 folder.
  - Pease, Henrietta (Faxon) Pease. A.MS. diaries; [v.p.] 3 Jul 1901-1923 Aug [1911]3 v., (1211)
  - Perry, Ben Edwin, 1892-; William Abbott Oldfather. TS.s. (carbon copy); [n.p., n.d.], (1212); 6s.(6p.)
    Also by H.E. Cunningham and C.R. Griffith.
  - Pharr, Clyde, 1883- A project for a variorum translation into English of the entire body of Roman law. TS. (mimeographed, unsigned); [n.p., 1933], (1213); 7s.(7p.)
  - Ryberg, Inez (Scott) 1901- [Outline of study] TS. (carbon copy, unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (1214); 2s.(2p.)
  - Ryberg, Inez (Scott) 1901- M.N. Obituary, G.C. Richards, 1867-1951. TS. (carbon copy) unsigned); [n.p.] 8 Feb 1951., (1215) T.; 2s.(2p.)
  - Washburn, Henry Bradford, 1869- A part of the service in memory of Henrietta Faxon Pease. TS. (unsigned); [n.p., Nov 1951], (1216); 5s.(5p.)
  - [Miscellaneous manuscripts], (1217); 1 folder.
  - [Miscellaneous printed material], (1218); 3 folders.